The petals fell like rain dampening my cheeks.
樱花落英缤纷 如雨般拂过脸颊
I was crying alone amid the raining petals.
在花雨之下 我独自哭泣
The warm sunlight of spring,
不论是春日暖阳
the summer sunshine through the trees,
还是夏天叶隙间的阳光
the sunbeams through the autumn clouds,
或是秋天云间投下的光
the morning light reflecting on snow...
还是纷纷雪花反射的朝霞
None of those would shine on me.
都未曾映照到我身上
I didn't even know what happiness was.
我对幸福一无所知
After all, any gleam of hope always disappeared right before my eyes.
因为任何微小的希望都会在眼前消散
I had lived my life always thinking
我曾一直是这么认为的
that my existence was not necessary in this world...
这个世界不需要我
Until that day when I met that man.
直到那一天我遇到那位大人
EPISODE 1 THE MEETING
第1集:相遇
This is awful!
这是什么?
That green tea is too bitter to drink!
这茶太涩了 难以下咽
I'm so sorry.
非常抱歉
Go remake it right now!
马上去重新泡一杯
Miyo, don't just sit there bowing. Hurry up.
美世 你还要在那里待多久?快点去
Yes, ma'am.
遵命
Excuse me.
我先告退了
I can't believe she can't even make green tea properly.
她连茶都泡不好
She should be ashamed as a member of the Saimori family.
身为斋森家的人 她不觉得羞耻吗?
Unlike you, Kaya, she's a clumsy girl. Just like that mother of hers.
不像你 香耶 她是个蠢丫头 和她妈妈一模一样
Kanoko. Are you trying to blame me?
香乃子 你是在怪我吗?
Well, she's your daughter, Shinichi.
她可是你的孩子啊
Spare me already. You know it was a long time ago.
饶了我吧 都过去多少年了
Good morning, Mr. Tatsuishi. What brings you here today?
早上好 辰石大人 今天有何贵干?
I need to have a little talk with Shinichi.
我有话对真一说
This is for your servants to eat.
这是给仆人们的慰问品
Oh, thank you for always being kind.
感谢您一直以来的照顾
It's my pleasure. I'll be going, then.
不用谢 我先去了
Mr. Tatsuishi was just here. I wonder if it was about a marriage offer?
辰石大人方才光临 是来求亲的吗?
The sisters are both getting to that age.
美世小姐和香耶小姐都到了年纪
Ms. Miyo is 19 years old already.
美世小姐都19岁了
But considering their father's attitude, it might be for Ms. Kaya and not her.
但是那位真一大人应该更中意 香耶小姐 而不是美世小姐
That's enough chatter, you two. Those who can't do laundry don't get fed!
你们在说什么闲话? 衣服都洗不好 小心吃不上饭
Will someone please come to the living room?
喂 来客厅一趟
Hey, Mrs. Saimori is calling!
快 斋森夫人叫你们呢
- We'll be right there!
-马上来
Marriage... offer?
求亲?
You're sweeping the garden today too? How diligent of you.
你今天也在扫庭院吗?真有活力
Koji.
幸次少爷
My father came to have a head-of-family meeting with your father.
家父来贵府与令尊商谈家族事务
I came as an attendant to him.
我是陪他来的
It's nice of you to come all the way.
辛苦您了
Actually, that was my excuse. I just wanted to talk to you, Miyo.
其实都是借口 其实我是想和你说话
Miyo, let me see your hand.
美世 伸手
Milk...?
牛奶?
Milk caramel. It's a candy that's sweet and delicious.
是奶糖 很甜很好吃
When I tried it for the first time, I was completely blown away.
我第一次吃的时候 觉得美味极了
I'm glad you liked it.
你喜欢就好
My older brother loves all things new and popular and he bought them.
这是我喜欢新鲜东西的大哥买的
It's very good.
非常好吃
If you want, I'll bring you more.
如果你想要 我随时都可以拿给你
If I can make you smile, then it's worth the price.
只要能让你展露微笑 这算不了什么
Thank you as always.
一直以来 谢谢你了
I wish we could spend time like this forever.
如果能一直这样就好
Miyo,
美世
I want to help you.
我想帮你
I feel like you're always saving me, Koji.
幸次少爷拯救了我
I'm just a plain guy, but I want to give you strength.
我虽然很平凡 但总有一天 我想能帮得上你
I'll do anything for you, for you to keep smiling.
只要是为了你 只要能让你一直欢笑
Hope you don't mind.
希望你不要介意
Father, is it okay to buy a new kimono to wear to Girls' School?
父亲大人 我能否买一件 在女校穿的新和服?
In that case, why don't you go buy a few new ones?
那干脆买个两三件如何?
Wow! Really?
真可以吗?
Thank you, Father!
谢谢您
Oh, Shinichi. You always spoil Kaya.
你真是的 太宠着香耶了
This kimono is getting tattered.
这件和服已经破破烂烂了
Miyo.
美世
Yes?
是
What do you usually do during the day?
你白天都在做什么?
I clean around the house.
家中上下的清洁工作
I see.
这样啊
Make sure you are here during the day, the day after tomorrow.
后天白天 你一定要留在家中
Understood?
明白吗?
Yes, sir.
遵命
He told me to be here, although I'm treated as a servant.
他竟然叫与仆人无异的我留在家中
It was an unnecessary request.
就算他不说
I never go outside the boundaries of this house anyway.
我也不能走出家门一步
Mother?
母亲大人?
Have either of you seen my mother?
你们看到我母亲了吗?
I think Mrs. Saimori is in the annex.
夫人在偏厅
Are you about to go out?
您要出门了吗?
Yes. I'm getting a new kimono made for the new semester.
我要为了新学期穿的和服量尺寸
But more importantly,
比起这个
Big Sister, shouldn't you wash your face?
姐姐大人 您洗洗脸如何?
You look terrible.
你的脸很难看
What?
什么?
Ms. Miyo, you have soot on your face...
美世小姐 您的脸上沾了灰
Don't you dare greet our guests looking like that, all right?
你可不要顶着这样一张脸去见客
You're already the embarrassment of the Saimori family.
本来就已经是斋森家的耻辱
I am sorry.
非常抱歉
Miyo...
美世
Koji.
幸次少爷
Good morning. It's rare to see you wearing Western clothes.
早上好 很少看你穿洋装
You look very good in them.
真的很适合你
Um, why did you come here today?
你今天是有什么事?
With my father?
和家父?
Here.
给你
I brought some sweets. Please share them with everyone.
我买了些点心 不介意的话和大家一起吃吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
Koji...
幸次少爷
Why does it have to be this way?
为什么会变成这样?
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐
Mr. Saimori is calling for you.
老爷叫您
What?
什么?
You're wanted in the parlor immediately.
让您马上去会客室
Yes, ma'am.
好的
You must be here during the day, the day after tomorrow.
后天白天 你一定要留在家中
Understood?
明白吗?
I shouldn't get my hopes up.
我不该抱有希望
It must be something bad.
肯定不是什么好事
A marriage offer from Koji...
与幸次少爷的婚约
I know I shouldn't hope for
我不该由此期待
something like that, but...
本应如此 可是我...
I'm here. It's Miyo.
是我 美世
Come in.
进来
Pardon me.
打扰了
Why do you look dazed?
你在愣什么?
Come into the room quickly.
能快点进来吗?
This meeting is about nothing other than the future of our family.
要说的不是别的
First, the arranged marriage with the Tatsuishi family.
是与辰石家的婚约和这个家的将来
I've decided to let Koji marry into the Saimori family and take over.
我决定让幸次入赘并继承斋森家
The one who will become his bride and preserve the Saimori family...
而辅助他支撑这个家的妻子人选
is Kaya.
是香耶
I was prepared for this.
我早有心理准备
Being treated like a servant as I am, I knew there was no way I could marry.
与仆人无异的我是不可能结婚的
I knew that it would never be that easy for me
我早就知道 我在这个家中 绝不可能轻易过上
to have my existence tolerated and to spend peaceful days living here.
平稳安宁的生活
Miyo, I decided you should marry and leave.
美世 我要将你嫁出去
You're marrying into the Kudo family.
对方是久堂家
Kiyoka Kudo will be your husband.
是久堂清霞
K-Kudo?
久堂?
That's great!
太好了
You get to be married to that famous Kiyoka Kudo.
你竟然能嫁给 那个赫赫有名的久堂清霞
That's too good for someone like you with no redeeming qualities.
对于一无是处的你过于高攀了
I'll look forward to seeing how many days you'll last being his wife.
姐姐大人到底能在 久堂家待几天呢?我很期待
Gather your belongings right away. You're going to the Kudos' house tomorrow.
马上收拾好你的行李 明早就去久堂家
Uh, Father--
-请问 父亲... -好了
If you understood, get ready quickly. Take extra care to be courteous.
你明白了就快点收拾行李吧 千万不要有无礼之举
Excuse me.
那我告退了
So, Koji. About the schedule for the engagement ceremony...
好了 幸次 关于你的订婚日程...
It doesn't seem like it'll stop raining.
雨一时半会停不了了
I went to the trouble of hanging out the laundry...
我好不容易把衣服晒出去
Miyo...
美世
Wait, what?
等等 什么?
Why me?
为什么是我?
As I said, I'm ordering you to become the husband of Kaya Saimori.
不要让我重复 你要入赘斋森家
Why all of a sudden?
为什么这么突然?
Didn't you say you wanted to help Miyo?
你想帮美世吧?
Don't worry. I asked Saimori for Miyo to be Kazushi's wife.
不要担心 我拜托斋森 把美世嫁给一志
By doing so, she can leave that house.
这样一来 她就能离开那个家
Don't you think that would set her down the happiest path?
这对她来说才是最幸福的 你说呢?
What about Miyo's feelings? And of all people, Kaya and me?
那美世会怎么想?偏偏是我和香耶
It's already been arranged.
已经定下来了
You must follow this decision for the sake of the prosperity of this family.
为了这个家的繁荣 你必须遵从这个决定
Do you understand?
明白了吗?
My mother's cherry tree.
母亲的樱花树
Whenever I was feeling down, coming here gave me peace of mind.
每当陷入低沉 我都会来这里汲取安慰
I guess I won't be able to come here anymore.
以后也不能来这里了吧
Thank you for always being here. Goodbye, Mother.
一直以来 谢谢您 永别了 母亲
Miyo.
美世
Koji.
幸次少爷
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm ashamed of my cowardice.
我真是不中用
In the end, I couldn't do anything.
到最后什么都做不到
It's not for you to apologize, Koji.
你不需要道歉
It's just bad luck.
只是运气不好
No, it's not just bad luck...
不 不是运气的事
It's all right. I might find happiness with whom I marry.
没关系的 嫁过去说不定能获得幸福
I don't blame anyone.
我不在意
So...
所以你
you don't resent me for this?
并不恨我吗?
Resent? I've forgotten that feeling a long time ago.
怨恨?我早就忘记这种感情了
I wanted to help you.
我想要救你的
I wanted to be able to laugh with you in a normal way like we used to.
我想和从前一样和你说笑
Because I--
因为我...
Koji?
幸次少爷?
Kaya.
香耶
What are you talking about?
你们在聊什么?
N... Nothing.
没什么
Oh, okay.
那就好
Koji.
幸次少爷
Thank you for all of your kindness until now.
一直以来多谢你了
Ms. Miyo, may I come in for a minute?
美世小姐 我能进来吗?
Yes, please.
请进
I have a message from your father. He said to wear this kimono
老爷吩咐 让您明天
when you depart tomorrow.
穿着这个出发
My father said to?
父亲他?
Listen closely, Ms. Miyo.
请听我说 美世小姐
Kiyoka Kudo is rumored to be a cold and merciless man.
听闻久堂清霞大人冷酷无情
Every fiancée has run away from him.
每一位未婚妻都逃走了
Please be careful.
万望小心
Thank you for your concern.
谢谢您的关心
Your belongings...
您的行李
That's all you have?
只有这些吗?
Most of what my mother left me has been thrown away.
母亲的物件都被丢掉了
This is all I have.
只剩这些
It must have been hard for you.
您应该很难过吧
Here, this is for you to eat on your way.
如果不介意 路上请吃这些吧
Thank you for your help.
多谢您
Take care of yourself, Ms. Miyo.
请多保重 美世小姐
I don't think a fancy kimono like this would ever suit me.
这么华丽的和服根本不适合我
I guess I've finally lost my fond memories as well as a house to call home.
我终于失去了归处和回忆
Is this the house?
是这里吗?
It's plainer than I imagined.
比我想的要朴素
Hello?
你好
Just a second, please.
请稍等
Who might you be?
请问您是?
I'm here because of the marriage arrangement with Mr. Kiyoka Kudo.
我本次前来是因为与 久堂清霞大人的婚约
Oh, Ms. Saimori. We have been waiting for you.
斋森小姐 我们正盼望您来呢
I work as a servant of the Kudo family. My name is Yurie.
我是久堂家的仆人 我叫由里江
I'm glad to make your acquaintance.
请多多关照
I've heard a lot about you. Please come in.
久闻大名 快请进
Thank you.
谢谢
The Young Master is in the study now.
少爷正在书房
If you would follow me, I'll show you the way there.
我马上带您过去
I am very pleased to meet you.
很高兴见到你
My name is Miyo Saimori.
我叫斋森美世
I hope you treat me kindly here.
请多关照
How long do you intend to bow that way?
你要这样多久啊?
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I wasn't asking for an apology.
我不是让你道歉
Please, you can raise your head now.
快 抬起头来
Y-Yes.
好的
Meeting this man on this day
今天见到他
was like a flower coming out of the snow.
就像是看到雪中开出的花
My life that had been shut off
我被停止的人生
I'm Kiyoka Kudo, the head of the Kudo family.
我是久堂清霞 是久堂家的家主
What a beautiful man.
好美的人